ladies and gentlemen good day and
welcome to the Q2 f523 and H1 fi23
earnings conference call of adani ports
and scz limited hosted by Centrum
broking Limited
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only more and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing start then 0 on a
touchstone phone please note that this
conference call is being recorded
I now hand the conference over to Mr
ashisha from Central broking limited
thank you and over to you
yes thank you for the introduction on
behalf of Centrum broking limited I uh I
welcome everybody to the adani course
and svz Q2 and H1 s523 earnings
conference call we heard from the
company management Mr karamadani who is
the CEO and whole time director of
Academy Sports and a to z Mr subrator
tripathi he's a CEO of post business Mr
Vikram Jesus Logistics
thank you Ashish good evening everybody
Welcome to the H1 FY 23 conference call
to discuss the operational and financial
performance for raniport and as he said
Limited you will be pleased to know that
despite economic headwinds globally
aps-cz has delivered its strongest half
yearly performance in the company's
history
wherein we recorded our highest ever
cargo volume revenue and a beta
talking about our cargo volume
aps-e-z handled record
177.5 million metric ton of thought of
total Cargo in the first half of the
year which is then 17 jump over the
preceding six months that is H2 of 8 by
22 and on a year-on-year basis it
increases 11 percent
the average monthly run rate of uh April
to September 2022 is well aligned to our
full year volume guidance of 350 to 360
million metric tons
a p h e z cross the 200 million metric
ton of cargo throughput milestone in the
initial 212 days of the financial year
which is another record for the company
on the revenue front we clock the
highest ever half yearly revenue of
rupees 10
317 crores which is a 16 growth year on
year
this Revenue growth is not only
supported by the volume increase but
also the improved realization even the
renegotiation of contracts at the start
of the financial year
we recorded the highest ever half yearly
Evita of rupees
6551 crores which is a good 21 jump over
the corresponding period last year our
Logistics business recorded for
year-on-year jump of 470 basis points in
ebitda margin to reach 29 percent
to grow cargo volume at the Port we are
trying our targeted capacity Edition
based on the market requirements at our
existing ports in August uh apftz
commission a six uh six lakh to you
Container Terminal facility at
gangavaram Port which will bring bring
in a new cargo type at this point we
have also added assets across our
Logistics business including two mmlp
three Agri Logistics rights with a
capacity of 0.1 million metric tons
uh six trades and 900 trucks for
providing the last mile connectivity
the MMS is inducted into business
include one at taloja in Mumbai and the
other one in ATV
the ICD tone at walking acquired from
navcat Logistics Corporation is one of
the largest ict's of India with a
capacity of 0.5 million metric tons it
will be it it has been integrated with
adani Logistics on 1st October
in the last two quarters apftz has been
successful with various bits we have
signed a concession agreement for
mechanization of around 5 million
metrics and birth at haldi airport in
West Bengal which takes our portfolio
which takes our food court footprint in
India 213.
we have also received an Loi for a
Greenfield development at rajput Port in
West Bengal
which we expect to Commission in the
next five years
on the logistics side we have received a
Loa from Food Corporation of India to
build silos across four locations in ut
and Bihar with a total capacity of 0.35
million metric ton which will take our
total Agri Silo capacity to 1.53 million
metric tons
and we have also been shortlisted as the
H1 beta for the Loney ICD in up from CWC
with that we are mmlp portfolio in India
will reach to a total count of 10.
I am pleased to note that the honorable
Supreme Court of India threw an order on
5th September 2022 restore apscc's right
to participate in the bidding of major
ports thereby putting to the rest the
wrong decision of certain Port
Authorities on disqualifying epscc from
the bidding process of major ports
in the last six months we have carried
out three large strategic Acquisitions
two are now hundred percent computed
which is Ocean Park ocean Sparkle and
gangavarampur
ocean Sparkle is India's leading
third-party Marine service service
provider with over 60 market share and
gangavaram Port is India's third largest
private sector four wherein we have
acquired the remaining 58.1 percent
state from the promoters post the nclt
approval in October
the third transaction which is scheduled
for completion within the next few weeks
is the hyperport company in Israel
with all in all organic and inorganic
investment progressing well a credit
profile continues to be strong with net
debt to a vector ratio at 3 which is
well within our guided rates in May 2002
I have announced uh
I have announced about apscc signing a
binding purchase agreement sorry inmate
220 uh
in May 22 I have announced about apscc
signing a binding purchase share
purchase agreement for the sale of
Myanmar asset the decision to diverse
was taken by the apscc board in October
2021 which was communicated to all key
stakeholders
in our May communication we have
highlighted that the asset sales will be
concluded after the achievements of
conditions precedent that are
Incorporated in the FDA even the
progress made in the CPS I am expecting
the divestment process to conclude in
the coming few weeks
for some more color on the operational
ESG and financial performance over two
years ago thank you Karan Bhai good
evening and hello everyone on the call
let me now give you an overview of the
performance and reports vertical talking
about cargo volumes APS is at clocked
record volume of 177.5 million metric
tons in H1 of fy23 this volume grow has
been contributed by more Sports
particularly Mundra krishnapatnam the
age and katupalli our Flagship course
Mundra has reflected an eight percent
year-on-year growth in cargo volumes the
boat has already touched 94 million
metric tons of cargo volumes support
contributed about 46 percent of the
total cargo share of APs event during H1
from the perspective of East Coast and
West Coast parity the cargo volume share
remains unchanged at 61 percent of
course on the west coast and 39 for our
course on the Eastern Coastline of India
this year on your cargo volume growth on
the East Coast was higher at 13 versus
10 percent on the East Coast looking at
the cargo baskets of H1 the dry cargo
share is about 54
containers contribute about 36 percent
of the total volume and liquids
including Cruise gas is about 10 percent
group gas is about 7.5 percent of the
total volumes
talking about containers APS is at
handle about 63 million metric tons of
container cargo during the first half
the volumes grew by five percent year on
year bundra continues to be India's
largest container handling port with
about 3.3 million metrics used in H1 of
FY 23 versus
2.96 million metric used by jnpt
therefore consulate consolidating itself
as the Gateway Force as far as exports
of India are confirmed between cars of
India is concerned our Flagship Force
now handles one part of the country's
social container cargo volumes we
believe that our focus on improving
Railway connectivity at Mundra singles
Windows service to the shipping line
integrated Supply Chain Solutions to end
customers and a partnership model with
large Shipping Lines through jv's
approach is helping us guide this volume
growth at Monroe so talking about the
tri-cargo segment the total cargo handle
in the first half is about 97 million
metric tons which is a jump of 18
percent year on year within this segment
coal grew by 28 percent year on year and
agri's products had a phenomenal growth
of about 273 percent year on year moving
to Liquid Cargo atheists that handles
Liquid Cargo 17.5 million metric tons
which is about almost flat on a year and
year basis in the last two to three
months we have signed several contracts
for different cargo types these include
five new container services at Mundra
and hazirak with a total cargo potential
of about 2 lakh tus per annum and four
large bulk contracts at gangavaram and
gamra ports with a cargo potential of
about 10 million metric tons per annum
we are also looking to get an additional
core volume of about three to three
point five million metric tons and the
question of optimum Port given the start
and commissioning of the new 800
megawatt power unit at mellow by ATP BCL
I would now thank thank you and hand
over to Vikram to update you on the
logistics model over to you Vikram
thank you good evening to everyone in
the call
let me give you an overview of the
performance at the logistics vertical
are there any Logistics witnessed a 24
year-on-year growth in real volume
to two lakh to lakh 22 944 to use
and a 43 year-on-year growth in terminal
volume to one lakh 92 000 39 days
this has been achieved with Roundup of
operations at killaraipur Logistics
parts
the commissioning of nagpur multimodal
Logistic Park at the start of the year
and the commissioning of taloja
multimodal Logistic Park during q1 this
year
with the acquisition of Tomb mmlp the
total count of operational mmts has
increased to nine
furthermore the logistic parks at
viruchend nagar and panipat are
currently under development
apwr vertical
trajectory with cargo volume being
doubled to 6.27 million with return on
why award basis
and with new circuits added from mines
to power plants to integrated steel
plants
the bulk cargo transportation is gaining
momentum
that has enabled us to more than double
the cargo versus the corresponding
period last year
in H1 FY 23 adani Logistics handled 6.27
million metric tons against 3.28 million
metric ton in q1 FY 22 in H1 FY 22. we
added six new rates during first half
and with that we now have 29 gpws rakes
in our statement
besides orders have been placed for a
total of 62 new trains under the gpwrs
framework which will be geared delivered
over the course of the next one year
coming to adani Agri Logistics
besides the three agree storage
terminals with the total capacity of
0.15 million metric fund commission
during H1 two more terminals one at
garbhanga and another one at samastipur
are now under construction with
commissioning likely in the next
financial year
additionally letter of interview from a
CI for four silos with a total capacity
of 0.35 million metric ton which will
take the total Silo capacity to 1.53
million metrics
in our warehousing business segment we
continued our journey to emergency as a
leading player in grade A warehousing
with focus on the commencement of new
projects including strategic
Acquisitions of warehousing assets
during H1 fy23 another 0.6 million
square feet of incremental capacity was
commissioned thereby taking the total
operational whereas the capacity to 1.4
million square feet
construction has been initiated on 10
million square feet of warehousing
capacity across six different locations
in Mundra nagpur moraya and Ahmedabad
ranoli in Baroda NRC in Mumbai
and panvel in NRC
we continue to work in line with our
vision to become an end-to-end
integrated Logistics service provider in
India by creating Logistics
infrastructure including multimodal
Logistics Parts warehouses grain silos
and complete rail solutions for
container liquid grain bulk and auto
garlic
I will now hand over to chiranjit to
update you on the EAC performance of the
aps event over to you
uh thank you Vikram and very good
evening to everyone on the call
let me start with our first Focus area
of carbon neutrality
here we have three action points first
is about the electrification of
equipment
by the end of this year we are likely to
complete electrification of most of the
crane
so a few other equipments we are already
doing Pilots for finding commercially
viable low carbon Solutions
our second action point is the sourcing
renewable electricity
APS is it has now decided for three
minutes 360 megawatt of capital
renewable capacity and the work on the
project has already started
third action point is on manual
forestation which is required for
sequestration of the emissions net
emissions
we initiated the sign group a
forestation on another 800 hectares of
land this is in line with our increased
Target
foreign hectares
coming to our second Focus area that is
of ensuring water supply from
non-competing sources at all our posts
we are currently evaluating possible
solutions at hazira Krishna patnam and
damra ports once the solutions are
implemented it will take us to 80
percent of apsus Target
of sourcing its entire water supply from
non-competing sources
for the past 12 months we have been
regularly engaging with the ESG rating
agency
there has been a constructive result of
this exercise with ADH is a
significantly improving its yearly score
in 2022 is to highlight our progress on
the ESB rating recently we received our
ESG assessment from SNP and Modi SNP has
scored us among the top 10.
in a peer group of 300 companies in the
transportation and transportation
infrastructure sector while Moody has
ranked us first among the transport and
Logistics Emerging Markets players with
this let me hand over to muthu for an
update on the financial performance over
to you
thank you I mean good evening to all of
you I'll first start off
with a quick paragraph on our quarterly
performance and then I'll move to the
half yearly performance for refer 23.
with cargo of 87 million ton we have
achieved the 15 growth year on year and
a revenue of 5211 crores it's a 33
growth and the corresponding growth in
the dirt
uh you know 3260 crores
and finally in terms of our net profit
after tax It's a 65 jump
uh at 1738 crores and after minority
and after TI The Profit after tax is
1677.
our EPS Transit 7.77 so that's for the
quarterly number now I'll move to uh
half yearly uh you know in terms of
total revenue we have achieved 10 230
crore and 70 crore which is the growth
of again 15 like in the quarter
and uh you know this fifteen percent is
on a year-on-year basis and this 15 is
despite a decline of 565 crores which is
our Revenue business segment uh from a
season
and this uh reduction in the aces were
revenue is already factored in our full
year guidance for sy23
and the growth is supported by 25 growth
in both revenue and a 32 growth in our
Logistics revenues
companies Consolidated
for the first half increased by 21 on a
year-on-year basis to
6551 crores
I'm not going to Port operation
for the first half we have we have seen
an increase of Revenue by 25 on a year
on media basis to
8967 crores and that ebitda also
increased by 24 on a viable wide basis
to
6236 crores
both of these are on the back of 11
percent increase in the cargo volume for
the first half
and an improved realization a
significant improved realization
overall Port margins stood at 70 percent
turning to Logistics business revenues
from this segment is a 721 crore which
is a growth of 32 percent on a
year-on-year basis
and it is contributed by all its sub
segments namely container rail bulk rail
terminal traffic and agree Logistics
the significant increase that you see in
the ebitda is actually a result of our
all-around effort
to diversify into bulk cargo
number one and number two to eliminate
loss making routes and number three to
generally improve efficiencies across
ebitda for this business grew by 67 to
212 crore and the margin expanded by 470
bills and the margin you get the margins
to the 29 percent
uh in terms of profit after tax for the
first half year it is 2915 crore and
that is a jump of 26 percent
compared to a corresponding period of
the last year
and this pack is after a pre-tax charge
of rupees 370 crores of non-cash Mark to
margin FX law
now in that context let me now move to
the next topic which is an update on our
effects on our risk management approach
traditionally we have been keeping all
our bond exposure
completely open
against the natural hedge of our future
Revenue
our annual revenue
have always more than covered the
maturities of the bonds of the
respective years whenever they mature
given the recent big exchange rate
movements that we have seen recently
we studied the options which
we can uh you within our existing risk
management policies
following this study we have embarked on
two approaches
the first one is actively hedging
especially the near-term one and the
second one is designating Bond against
our future Revenue exposure like you see
in some of the leading companies in the
marketplace
in this designation exercise
born the first designated by mapping and
earmarking revenues of
immediately ensuing month
as of the rate of maturity of these
bonds
and once this designation of Revenue is
done any Forex movement either loss or
gain
posts such designation date is no longer
included in the extraordinary item which
is below the ebitda but is included in
other comprehensive income Otis are
short in the pl account which is below
the path
as you will know
this OPI
is not included in the EPF calculation
the net gains are losses which are
accumulated in this
particular head will be moved to the
revenue line as the gains or losses of
the revenue in the months
when the designated bond mature and the
revenues for those moments are for those
months crystallized
as we have commenced this approach now
we have given a lot more detail
in the presentation that we have
calculated in the form of an annexure
and in that lecture we have also
included when the recycling will happen
by the year and where we have designated
the bonds
uh with that let me actually move to the
next topic which is actually cash flow
a company has generated very healthy
cash flow
and with that internally generated cash
flow
we have met our enhanced level of capex
which is the first half of
4015 crore
and we have funded acquisition which is
to the tune of 1500 crores
we have repaid loans which is again
covered full details in the cash flow
statement in the presentation
close to 6000 crores
and we are still left with cash flows in
the company
and finally after all these things are
leveraged is
three times instead of a bit down
so after the cash flow let me just
quickly move to highlight that in terms
of rating we continue to enjoy
investment grading investment grade
ratings by all credit trading agencies
and finally before I conclude let me
point you to page number 20.
which is actually the written on Capital
employees I wish to bring to your notice
that we have to improved our return on
Capital employed across all the posts
and across all our business
so with that let me actually conclude
the section on financials and hand it
back to run by for concluding remarks
so let me
just six months of si 23. uh ATAC rate
recorded the strongest half yearly
performance in the history of the
company with a record cargo volume
Revenue indicator
our integrated business model with an
end-to-end service from 4K to the
customer gate is providing to be a
material differentiator versus RPL and
enabling us to win customers and improve
their stickiness
with India likely to be the best
performing economy globally in 2022 and
23. we remain confident on uh of apscc's
growth story we continue to be on track
to achieve our full year guidance of 350
to 360 million metric ton of cargo
volume and an ebitda of 12 200 to 12 600
crores while also working on our organic
and inorganic process
with focus on sustainable development
aps-cz is all set to emerge uh as a
global force in the port and integrated
transport utility segment with this we
can open the lines for question and
answer
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on the Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and
two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question can assembles
we have a first question from the line
of Mohit Kumar from Dan Capital please
go ahead
and congratulations on a very very good
quote and uh making some successful
acquisition uh so my first question is
on the on the financials uh the uh while
the cargo has grown by 11 percent in H1
your uh your your revenues have grown by
what explains this is that some is this
to do with cargo mixing the quarter uh
or is some non-pot revenues which can
explain this jump
so it's uh it's it's both partners and
absolute increase in our pricing uh
which we did at the start of the year
and a lot of the contracts which uh got
expired over the course of the last six
months we were able to get an absolute
increase in the pricing over there and
the second is also because of the mix in
the uh in the cargo uh these are the
main two main reasons
no we have not received any any input
so lastly on this around on the
financials again there's a lot of Forex
in console and standard basis there is a
huge difference so generally these
standing can solve foreign
reconcile this number
yeah sure see you might recall that all
our bombs were sitting in actually the
whole group uh whereas our effects
designated income uh is across uh APA
season as well as a subsidiaries so the
designated Bond exercise that we have
done we have done only in the uh
consolidated so the 370 Crews charge
that you actually see which is MTM loss
uh is uh after actually the exercise of
designated bonds so what you see in the
Standalone uh I you know we haven't done
the designation of bonds uh in the
Standalone Financial so uh the
difference between the 9 billion and the
four billion which is 370 that I
mentioned is actually in the oci line in
the Consolidated business the
Consolidated Financial
understood the tank we have better thank
you
we have our next question from the line
of Atul tiwari from City please go ahead
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
barani Vijay Kumar from spark Capital
please go ahead sir
yeah good evening what portion of this 4
billion US dollar that is designated
bonds
2.8 billion round number and order the
3.9 billion dollar outstanding
okay so the OCA uh portion of this Forex
impact of 400 404 crores that we see
that's related to that 2.8 billion
designated points
okay if I see the cash flows for the
first half there's been a four thousand
crores of capex and about 1400 gross of
acquisition
being done uh how much would this be for
the full year sir the full capex and the
remaining acquisition for the year how
much would it be in there
yeah the Fourier guidance given is 8600
crore so we continue to maintain at this
point in time our guidance
and so that will be another 4000 cross
in the second half so can you highlight
in which assets it would happen
in our original guidance at the
beginning of the year and uh more or
less the same at this point in time
there is no material change to that
okay and the 1400 crores of acquisition
is
High support So hyperport funding uh
will happen in the second half and uh
you know what we gave as the original
guidance we are still working towards
that in terms of financing pattern and
uh you know uh closer to the time when
we actually do the financing uh you know
we will
um you know sort of update the market
with any changes
to the financing pattern
okay so thank you
thank you
yes please go ahead no I uh uh
congratulations
a global economic environment and also
the trade activity uh uh would you
appreciate your uh your guidance for the
second half of Current financial work or
if you can give us some some sense on uh
fi 24 and fy25 uh your view on what can
be the volume opportunity and how do you
see this uh these two Financial groups
like from a from a volume point of view
that'll be very helpful yeah so I uh as
you know that we had come out with our
uh five years uh strategy plan and we
had come out with 500 million ton of
volume handling by fy25 I think we are
well on track to achieve that guidance
and uh we we believe we are quite
confident that we will reach that by
fy25
but thanks uh just what a little broader
question in terms of the opportunity in
redeem India as a as a as a port you
spoke about uh about the few missing
blocks and there are a couple of things
which are completely Greenfield project
which we won recently and we are
expanding there if you can give us some
sense of from a from a decadal point of
view which is the which is the target
opportunity which you are looking you
may not want to name it in specific but
just give us some flavor in that sense
where are we seeing ourselves both
within India and our surrounding
geography will be very very helpful
please
yeah so I think within India we keep
looking for opportunities both within
major ports as well as any private ports
which come up for uh which come up for
sale uh within uh major ports the
government of India is read out a very
good plan in terms of the whole
monetization and as part of gatisha P
scheme and we we look for I mean we we
keep evaluating those opportunities and
uh you know keep plugging in where we
where we don't have a position uh on the
private side uh uh you know
they're not much of opportunity which we
can talk about right now but we keep
evaluating as and when it comes and we
look at more from a value value
iterative deals point of view
in in terms of neighboring countries uh
uh right now we are there in Myanmar I
mean in Sri Lanka and Israel we are
looking at opportunities in uh Eastern
Africa we're looking at opportunities in
Bangladesh and in uh in in some of the
Southeast Asian countries uh
predominantly high growth countries with
high consumption or high manufacturing
base
so these are the kind of opportunities
we look out for and we actively we are
actively scouting
uh thank you just follow up last sorry
uh uh do we have any irr or a creative
mind uh in terms of the future growth
opportunity or will be kind of okay
the location is very strategic products
and you don't like comparability
so so as you know we have a capital
allocation policy which is approved by
the board and it clearly states that all
new Investments have to be generating a
return of irr of 16 and above and uh
unless it is very strategic but so far
all the Acquisitions that we have done
we look at 16 and above thank you so
much I wish you all the best
thank you
for reminder to participants to press
on the line of Smith shade from Redan
please go ahead
hello
thank you
we have our next question from the line
of Priyanka vishwas from nomura Holdings
please go ahead
so my first question is uh regarding uh
can you just highlight certain timelines
or something but regarding let's say
lenses or monetization from the AC unit
angle so we are hearing a lot of things
like a copper plant and then probably
some green hydrants set up so can you
just provide some timelines and expected
incomes
expected income flows maybe from the
next two three years
so I think uh all the guidances that we
have given so far does not take into
account any age I mean a large part of
those income uh and as I said the reason
we are not giving those guidance is
because it is uh bulky in nature and the
timing of it is very difficult to to
give but these incomes we expect in the
next uh you know these land sales to
happen over the course of next three to
four years then
uh so can you uh provide a Quantum like
how much land base available with you
let's say across all the ports uh
besides Mundra and potentially how much
monetization in a let's say a blue sky
scenario that we can be looking at
you think uh it's very hard to give you
that exact number as you know in Tamra
and in Krishna patnam we have roughly uh
roughly 6 000 acres of land other than
Mundra where we have 40 000 Acres uh but
but as I said that these land incomes
are bulky in nature they are one time in
nature and it's very hard to give a
prediction in terms of how much income
we will generate out of this but as I
said there are a lot of these
opportunities which we are working on to
develop the code based ecosystem and as
in when we we are confident or we have
some visibility of when the income will
come we will given our guidance and
we'll give a sufficient time uh uh to uh
for for all of you to put in put into
big into your model
and the last question from my height I
see we have been uh the logistics
business of course uh it has improved on
the roce somewhat in this uh particular
first half so going forward like uh for
all your businesses you typically Target
like 16 Roc types so can you give us
some sense of that trajectory how we
will achieve this 16 levels uh and uh I
will which which are going to be the
drivers in a big way to derive
profitability
yeah you I'll request we come to answer
but in detail but just to give you broad
broad headline uh uh the gpws rate
business where we are expanding it's a a
aggressively uh the uh Agri Logistics
business and the warehousing business
these three business will will generate
uh are the ones which will push uh the
the overall Logistics business apart
from the container but these three
businesses will generate a Rosy higher
of 16 uh in the coming years and I'll
request
a request we come to add more on YouTube
and so uh
I I completely agree with what current
is said but the only thing is that to
clarify the timings of this Rosie which
will be obtained will be different for
the different verticals that we're
talking about
the first one to hit the block and to
see a immediately application
that will be introduced in the last in
the next one year because that will be
instantaneous Revenue instantaneous gain
in ebitda
and then it will be followed up by The
Rosy improvements as and when we start
uh putting on the lease and putting the
agreement warehousing side of projects
on the block with FCI followed by all
the warehouse construction which is
right now 10 million square feet in in
construction as in then they start
getting uh put on leads they will also
start delivering the rot so the timing
is different but uh I think in the next
uh
three years
we should look at uh you know between
our Target upward of eight percent to
even 16 which is the ultimatum and the
and the end result that we have planned
in this business model
thank you so much
thank you
question from the lineup for our Jain
from HSBC please go ahead
thank you
very much
it's been quite courageous
sorry you're not Audible
am I better
and try to be very concise
guidance I mean it seems quite quite
courageous to put the number in this
sensor what gives you your confidence is
that your view on India's ability to
continue to import with your at least
again market share or is it more like
any shortfall can be managed by
inorganic acquisition or do you see any
any doubts and risk to those guidance
and that's my first question maybe if
you can answer that next question
I think our guidance of 350 to 360 this
is uh uh you know we are very confident
we are looking at a lot of the data from
uh group companies as well as from uh
from our partners and we expect uh we we
do believe that India is in a growth in
a very good space economically and we
don't see growth uh growth coming down
any anytime soon uh I think we we expect
GDP to grow at around seven percent uh
and with that we expect a trade to grow
at around uh 10 to 11 percent uh I think
these are the main reasons why we we are
very confident and obviously
um as as manufacturing base in the
country is increasing and as the push
for manufacturing is happening we we are
seeing energy consumption increasing
across the board and which in turn
obviously helps the trade because India
Imports most of our energy so that is
one and then obviously second is uh we
are seeing significant amount of private
capex happening and we don't see a
Slowdown over there so in which in turn
again we we do see a lot of uh you know
a lot of trade movement happening the
nature of the trade might keep changing
so we the shares in in our view we will
see more growth on the bulk side than on
the container side but I think overall
we are very confident of reaching this
this guidance of 350 to 360.
okay and that's very very helpful in
that time and then my next question
please on on the slide that captures the
roce when we look at the RFC of each of
the businesses verticals they've seen a
mask Improvement but at a consolidate
level uh it seems to subdued so if you
have considered right includes one of
the businesses which are not building
building the return and secondly maybe I
could not hear you well could you could
explain the rationality of
the rational behind changing your your
way to recognize the effects losses from
from your password exercise
funneling through the pnl versus the new
approach thank you
sure
so to your first question uh basically
we have
a lot of Greenfield projects both new
projects as well as expansions that are
happening in our current site which are
sitting in cwip or we are carrying cash
to fund those uh expansions that we have
already sort of announced over the next
two three years
so you know if you back that out in the
calculation you will actually get a Roc
which is a true picture of delivering
projects and uh you know these projects
that we are currently undertaking will
also start delivering uh you know in the
next three to four years so you will see
uh return on Capital employed for a
company as a whole improving uh at that
point in time
uh these are planned capex so therefore
you know they're tracking our uh you
know sort of our plan
uh in terms of effects basically you see
the reason is uh you know with these
significant movements in the FX rate
that are happening in the market uh all
such movement call for Action right so
we went to the drawing board and we said
what are the options that we have
to actually truly reflect the underlying
operating performance of the company
are there any new uh you know sort of
tools that we have to use that is within
our current policy but that we are not
currently using
so two things that came out one is
active hedging wherein you know in a
rising market like this uh you know
we've started uh you know sort of uh
doing you know forward uh we will as a
company build expertise and uh you know
build on that active aging as we go but
while we have done that uh we also
studied what uh other Capital intensive
business in the marketplace is doing uh
the very underlying rationale for doing
any bond
you know and then call it a natural
hedge is because we do have dollar
revenue and by Nature these revenues
will come in future uh and uh you know
liabilities are sitting the bonds are
sitting in our lab uh balance sheet
today
so uh under the current accounting
standard we need to provide for Mark to
Market losses and that does not actually
give the underlying uh performance so
therefore what we have said is to bring
in the discipline of saying which bond
is designated against which years
Revenue
uh so we picked the bond from the
portfolio totaling to 2.8 billion
dollars and assigned Revenue
against those bonds and the moment we do
that accounting standard demand that we
moved profit and loss of profit or loss
for the period arising out of M term
away from the current extraordinary line
item to oci line item so that is what we
have done under the Indus 109 which is a
requirement okay but the fund the
underlying reason is actually to map the
revenues against the bond and to
demonstrate the discipline of how we
have uh you know read out the maturity
to match our underlying exposure
that will be done
so Myanmar one of the conditions
residents is completion of the project
uh we haven't actually completed the
project it is underway and uh you know
it should get over shortly I mean uh
once the project is completed we should
be able to close the deal
foreign
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
[Music]
pulkit thanks for taking my question
just one question if you could uh
highlight what the interest cost for the
next couple of years uh we should build
in uh given the the rise in rates I
understand we have bonds but if you
could just highlight what is the
interest cost we should bake in for the
next two years based on the increased
rates globally
fixed rate
so there is very very little which is
actually the working capital type and
that too is very very small which is
Market driven and that also actually you
know we still get very competitive rates
so you know there is no change in
interest rate uh you know compared to
what you're seeing today
of Interest approximately in that state
absolute amount of interest will change
okay that's helpful thank you
so I wanted to know about the fact that
uh the gross that increased by five
percent but the net debt has increased
by 27 percent
so in which page are you referring to
please uh no sir I'm calculating on a Yu
y basis uh in September 21 the Gross
State and net date and uh in uh in
September 22 the cross data meant that
so gross state has increased by five
percent in uh compared yui but net debt
has increased 27 percent
uh maybe we can actually take you
through offline uh that number doesn't
sound right to uh me intuitively
actually our net debt if anything is uh
sort of gone down
uh the reason why our gross jet has gone
up uh are twofold one is we have
borrowed marginally more for the new
project but also there is a 2000 crore
increase in the gross jet on account of
uh you know interim effects
but we can we can work offline with you
and uh take you through but that number
doesn't sound right okay so I would like
some guidance on that yeah please we can
do that okay
yourself
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
Amisha from Bank of America please go
ahead
yep thanks for the opportunity uh my
question actually is to Karen uh you
know when you spoke about the
international inorganic acquisition
opportunities uh earlier the thinking uh
was to do only Greenfield projects uh in
JV mode uh is that still the thinking uh
you know the reason why I asked is that
that would effectively mean uh you know
the percentage of capital deployed in
international is only going to rise
gradually is that the way we should
think about it still
yeah so uh
majority of it is right it will be
inorganic Green Field uh through through
JV mode uh similar to what we've done in
Sri Lanka or uh uh you know so something
like that uh however uh if we do look at
I mean if we do get attractive
opportunities like Israel we would look
at it but those are that most of it we
would be looking at is JV mode and uh
Greenfield development
okay uh on adani logistic uh you know
earlier uh primarily our growth was
coming from handling domestic cargo as
opposed to exim uh again uh just a
clarification is that uh still uh the
way and uh and and the subset question
to that is that how much is the FCI
warehouses getting converted to silos
that you're doing uh a part of the
domestic cargo growth uh within academic
Logistics
so let me just uh clarify over here our
adani Logistics mainly did exam and not
domestic uh 80 of their volume was
examined 20 was domestic and it
continues to be in that part of that
range
um in terms of Agri Logistics as you
know that more and more silos are coming
up uh for forbidding uh we've already
got uh we won we we are the H1 4.35
million metric ton of uh of new silos
which are coming up uh and uh we expect
another 2 million tons of uh of uh FCI
silos which will be coming up as part of
the Hub and spoke bidding so we expect
uh you know uh as as we had given in our
five-year guidance that we looked at uh
bringing this business up to almost 3
million tons of storage we are well
within we are very confident we would
reach that by 525
and and my final question is actually on
the major major boards opportunities uh
that you were talking about uh so
is that going to be a substantial part
of our business uh as you think about uh
you know the volume growth Target that
you put out for the 525 uh or or is is
it just one of uh Port opportunities
that you that we would look at within
major ports and we will continue to look
at the landlord models
it's from the existing asset it does not
take into account any new access that we
will add between now and 25 uh in major
posts we would look at selectively uh
based on uh the kind uh kind of
footprint and strategically where we
don't have a presence those are the
places we would look at to help us
consolidate in terms of our market share
but it will be very selective in nature
makes sense uh thank you very much Karen
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
nikhil abhyankar from Dam Capital please
go ahead
yes sure
thanks for the opportunity for most of
the questions are answered this I've got
one bookkeeping question can you give
the revenue and editor split for q1 and
Q2 fi 23 for oats and non-votes
still the total revenue we saw was 10270
crores and out of which the port revenue
is 8967 crores
[Music]
and this is for the first
half and uh if you wanted actually for
five two one one was the total revenue
uh okay let me just read out the total
revenue just a second please and you
would
uh okay so if you can note down the
number uh q1 total revenue is 5058 and
Q2 total revenue is five two one one
okay
okay okay and then as far as the port is
concerned it's four five one zero four
quarter one and four four five eight
four Quarter Two
okay
and so
oh you want to repeat that as well yeah
okay okay so put a bit done uh is three
one seven zero for
first quarter 3066 for second quarter
and totally beta is three two nine zero
and three two six zero so uh sure so if
you have written handy can you also give
a comparable for Q to fi 22
yeah I have Q2 FY 22
is uh
you want to start from revenue
yeah
so food revenue is three three nine
eight total revenue is three nine two
three
that's all from
we have our next question
please go ahead
hi so so uh just wanted to understand
like uh most of our uh volume increase
in this course has come on an absolute
this is a majority of it has come from
cold
um increasing cold volumes so do you see
this as sustainable especially
Consulting that container growth was
quite soft three or five percent I
believe
so this is the first question and
secondly uh you spoke about the exchange
being one of the reasons why Revenue
growth has been higher than the volume
growth so getting through a bit more
like on this like what kind of uh go uh
has a higher realization and however
maybe higher margin also these are my
two questions
yeah thank you uh of course on the cargo
volumes uh see the as we have guided the
coal has seen a significant growth and
you've seen that the dry segment has
grown from an equi 22 to an H1 and fy23
from 50 to 54 this is foiled by a very
strong rally in the coal and which is
understandable with the high energy
consumption which has been at a all-time
high in India and also the fact that the
growth fields are looking to sustain it
a we believe that the engine requirement
of phone will continue to be high in H2
also the fact that we've been able to
Garner new contracts as well as postal
code movement is concerned between what
is on the real come see route from the
landlocked mines in jharkhand Orissa
chattisgarh through our course in
gangavaram dhamra into the receiving
ports at krishnapatham which makes it a
you know at both our ports as well as
into the other southern part houses
consumption we're also working on the
East-West transfers that government is
talking of at February National stage
but the growth is going to come
primarily from these two exim as well as
domestic goal as far as the other
volumes are concerned the container does
need to be fairly flat although there is
a little bit of aspiration as to how it
is growing we've seen that the rally in
the festival season has been good so we
have boiled with a sentiment that the
impulse will start coming in and
especially engineering Goods which has
been a rally over the last two years as
far as India's exposed performance is
concerned will do will certainly come
back and if you look at the country's
choices they're getting into as
Government clarified getting more into
southeast Asia High consumption and high
growth economies and that should sustain
the volumes yet notwithstanding the
global slowdown that has happened so
volume wise all will be The Driver
without a doubt
uh in fact the other aspect of coal is
also the cooking cold we've seen this
market share consolidation mostly in our
Eastern ports uh we are looking at these
steel plants are on a you know the first
half has been a little subdued uh
because of the the consumption globally
the second half is seeing a growth and
we are seeing these signs of recovery on
cooking coal especially in the larger
plants of Steel authority of India as
well as a Tata steel a boat where we are
very well placed in our course in dhamra
and gangavaram particularly and in
krishnapatnam as far as general steel is
concerned for this plant so this
alignment and the choice of waste strong
bonds with the major consumers gives us
the confidence that we'll be able to
sustain this dry cargo growth
your second question on uh realization
of higher car goals do you like to take
that
see with respect to the realizations uh
when karanbai mentioned about the change
in the mix it is also the change in the
mix between the containers
right so if it is exempt versus Transit
meant there is a different realizations
so in this current year we have seen a
very high share with respect to the
accent and that's the reason the
realizations are much better I hope that
answers thank you
light has disconnected
we have our next question the line of
ashisha from Centrum broking limited
please go ahead
yeah thanks so this is two questions
from my side one second uh update what
is the on ground status as far as the
winning jump as it is concerned because
we also keep reading a lot of news flow
around uh local protests Etc so any
update will help
uh
two updates on Virginia first on the vgs
which the government of India has
finally sanctioned you are aware that we
get a component of close to 814 cores of
VGA the government of India has finally
sanctioned that we are expecting that to
come in and so that the project is
ongoing as for the project execution is
concerned you'd be aware that in the in
the last year
progress and normally both
when we open up the line the project is
being commissioned both from the land
and from the Marine side so we have two
places
to do the Breakwater they're all well
fed as of today we have seen every day
for the Quarry Stones coming into the
two locations as far as the agitation is
concerned we are aware that it is likely
misled we're also aware that the
government of Kerala is entirely
supportive and that there is a very
affirmative action on behalf of the high
courts of honorable high court of Kerala
which have been very supportive and have
given instructions that this education
should be lifted for it as we speak to
you we are we are expecting that this
whole situation to be cleared in another
group of fortnight and he seems the
monsoon Monsoon has seated in just about
a fortnight back so you haven't lost
time and we're very very confident of
the earlier guidance given that the
sport will be commissioned in the
calendar year 23 and we have taken all
the affirmative actions in line the
cranes which are coming in and it is
going to be a state-of-the-art
world-class Terminal A automated
terminal so we went into line these are
small aberrations and I'm sure we will
be entirely over with that very soon
right so second question uh on the capex
so this year for the FI 23 is the
reiterated 8600 code catex but from a
slightly medium term from a three-year
perspective would we be looking at an
annual capex of uh similar range of
let's say nine to ten thousand codes is
that a number one should plug it
I think uh the way to look at is
ports will continue with which okay will
have capex around two to two and a half
thousand code the logistics business
mainly warehousing and agree Logistics
as we keep scaling up that will continue
to have a 4 000 cores of traffic so I
would say on an average you can take
between six to eight is what we will
continue to spend in the coming in the
coming uh in the coming uh few years
right and this would include assets like
Sri Lanka uh everything everything
right but not Haifa right Haifa would be
an inorganic definition to this that's
it
right right so yeah I mean that's it uh
that's it from my side and uh so on
behalf of central Brooklyn I would like
to thank all the participants for
attending this call and thank the
management for giving us this
opportunity I would like to hand over to
the management for any closing comments
thank you sir thank you thank you
everybody for joining and if there are
any questions uh uh karanjit is great to
answer and the team is there to answer
thank you have a good good evening
thank you on behalf of central broking
limited that concludes the conference
call thank you for joining us and you
may not disconnect your lines
the conference is no longer being
recorded